Guide to the Susan H. Douglas political Americana collection, [1783?]-1961.
Douglas, Susan H. Political Americana Collection, [1783?]-1961
- Series XVIII. Textiles
  - Washington "The Effect of Principle, Behold the Man" Textile, ca. 1806; 2214.TX0047 (Box 107)
  - "I Like Ike" Textile, ca. 1952; 2214.TX0048 (Box 104)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.TX0049 (Box -)
  - Blaine-Logan Portrait Textile, ca. 1884; 2214.TX0051 (Map-case -)
  - Cleveland-Stevenson "Our Candidates 1892" Portrait Textile, 2214.TX0052 (Box 104)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Morton "Our Choice" Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0053 (Box 105)
  - McKinley Western Hemisphere Portrait Handkerchief, 1899; 2214.TX0054 (Box 108)
  - Benjamin Harrison "Protection, Home Industries" Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0055 (Box 103)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.TX0056 (Box -)
  - Centennial Celebration by Manhattan Lodge, I.O.B.B., 1889; 2214.TX0057a (Box TBD)
  - Benjamin Harrison "Protection" Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0058 (Box 103)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Morton "Protection to American Industries" Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0059 (Box 103)
  - Benjamin Harrison "True Blue Republican Protection Home Industries" Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0060 (Box 103)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Reid "The Union And The Constitution Forever" Portrait Handkerchief, 1892; 2214.TX0061 (Box 105)
  - Cleveland-Stevenson "Union is Strength" Portrait Handkerchief, 1892; 2214.TX0062 (Box 103)
  - Hayes-Wheeler "International" Textile, ca. 1875-1876; 2214.TX0063 (Box 108)
  - Benjamin Harrison "Protection to Home Industries" Portrait Textile, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0064 (Box 108)
  - Cleveland-Hendricks Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1884; 2214.TX0065 (Box 103)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Morton "1888" Portrait Handkerchief, 2214.TX0066 (Box 105)
  - Benjamin Harrison "Protection To American Labor" Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0067 (Box 105)
  - World's Fair Dedication Program, ca. 1904; 2214.TX0068 (Box 103)
  - Benjamin Harrison "Protection To American Labor And American Industries" Handkerchief, 1888; 2214.TX0069 (Box 105)
  - Garfield-Arthur "The Union And The Constitution Forever" Portrait Handkerchief, 1880; 2214.TX0070 (Box 105)
  - Declaration of Independence, ca. 1876; 2214.TX0071 (Box 105)
  - "I Like Ike!" Handkerchief, ca. 1952; 2214.TX0072 (Box 107)
  - "I Like Ike!" Handkerchief, ca. 1952; 2214.TX0073 (Box 103)
  - "I Like Ike!" Handkerchief, ca. 1952; 2214.TX0074 (Box 107)
  - "Harrison & Morton" Portrait Textile, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0075 (Box 105)
  - McKinley-Hobart "Protection, Prosperity, Sound Money" Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1896; 2214.TX0076 (Box 103)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Reid "Our Choice" Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1892; 2214.TX0077 (Box 103)
  - Bryan-Sewall Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1896; 2214.TX0078 (Box 106)
  - McKinley-Hobart "Protection, Sound Money" Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1896; 2214.TX0079 (Box 106)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Morton Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0080 (Box 106)
  - Cleveland-Thurman "Our Choice" Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1888; 2214.TX0081 (Box 105)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Portrait Textile, ca. 1904; 2214.TX0082 (Box 150)
  - The "Maine" Well Remembered: Manila Captured, August 13th, 1898; 2214.TX0083 (Box 154)
  - Theodore Roosevelt "First in War, First in Peace ..." Portrait Handkerchief, 2214.TX0084 (Box 154)
  - Grant "Let Us Have Peace" Textile, ca. 1868; 2214.TX0085 (Box 107)
  - Bryan-Kern Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1908; 2214.TX0086 (Box 106)
  - Cleveland Portrait Textile, ca. 1884; 2214.TX0087 (Box 107)
  - William Henry Harrison "Harrison and Reform" Portrait Textile, ca. 1840; 2214.TX0088 (Box 106)
  - General Harrison Welcomes Two of His Old Comrades, ca. 1840; 2214.TX0089 (Map-case -)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt "The Great President" Portrait Textile, ca. 1945; 2214.TX0091 (Box 106)
  - Hancock-English Portrait Handkerchief, ca. 1880; 2214.TX0092 (Box 105)
  - Cleveland-Stevenson "Our Candidates 1892" Portrait Handkerchief, 2214.TX0093 (Box 106)
  - Theodore Roosevelt-Fairbanks "The Right Men in the Right Place" Portrait Handkerchief, 1904; 2214.TX0094 (Box 106)
  - Parker-Davis "Democracy's Choice" Portrait Textile, 1904; 2214.TX0095 (Box 106)
  - Bryan-Sewall "Free Coinage" Portait Handkerchief, 1896; 2214.TX0096 (Box 106)
  - The Eisenhower Toile, ca. 1956; 2214.TX0097 (Box TBD)
  - The Eisenhower Toile, ca. 1956; 2214.TX0098 (Box TBD)
  - G.O.P. Republican Party Handkerchief, ca. 1956; 2214.TX0099 (Box 107)
  - "I Like Ike" Handkerchief, ca. 1952; 2214.TX0100 (Box 154)
  - "I Like Ike" Handkerchief, ca. 1956; 2214.TX0101 (Map-case -)
  - William McKinley Portrait Towel, ca. 1896-1901; 2214.TX0104 (Box 108)
  - Eisenhower Portrait Needle Painting, ca. 1957-1960; 2214.TX0105 (Box 108)
- Series XIX. Wearing Apparel
  Wearing Apparel: This series consists of a variety of politically-related costume items, including neckties, hats and caps, suspenders, and even underwear. There is significant overlap between the "Wearing Apparel" and "Parades" categories.
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt Portrait Necktie, ca. 1936; 2214.WA0001 (Box 155)
  - "Willkie" Brown Necktie, ca. 1940; 2214.WA0002 (Box 155)
  - Willkie Blue Necktie, ca. 1940; 2214.WA0003 (Box 155)
  - Truman Portrait Necktie, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0004 (Box 155)
  - Dewey Portrait Necktie, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0005 (Box 155)
  - "Wallace '48' " Maroon Necktie, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0006 (Box 155)
  - Robert A. Taft Maroon Portrait Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0007 (Box 155)
  - "I Like Taft" Portrait Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0008 (Box 155)
  - Stevenson Blue Portrait Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0009 (Box 155)
  - Kefauver "I Like Estes" Portrait Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0010 (Box 155)
  - Eisenhower "Ike" Brown and White Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0011 (Box 155)
  - Eisenhower "Ike" Blue and White Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0012 (Box 155)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Portrait Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0013 (Box 155)
  - Eisenhower "I Like 'Ike'" Yellow Bow Tie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0014 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Blue Bow Tie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0015 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Navy Blue Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0016 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Military Portrait Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0017 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower "Everybody Likes Ike!" Multilingual Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0018 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower "I Like 'Ike' " Blue Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0019 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower Blue Pattern Necktie, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0020 (Box 156)
  - Stevenson "I Like Adlai" Veil, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0028 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Black Veil, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0029 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "Ike" Brown Veil, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0029a (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Women's Gloves, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0030 (Box 165)
  - Boys' "I Like Ike" T-shirt, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0031 (Box 82)
  - Truman-Barkley Women's Underpants, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0032 (Box 141)
  - Dewey-Warren Women's Underpants, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0033 (Box 141)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Women's Sunglasses, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0034 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "Ike" Cufflinks and Tie Clasp, ca. 1952; 2214.WA0035 (Box 165)
  - "Dewey for President" Portrait Necktie, ca. 1944-1948; 2214.WA0036 (Box 156)
  - Wallace-Taylor "Win With Wallace" Light Blue Portrait Necktie, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0037 (Box 150)
  - "Win With Wallace" Green Portrait Necktie, ca. 1948; 2214.WA0038 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower "Ike: The Heart of America Is With You" Portrait Necktie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0039 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower Five Stars / "I Like Ike" Necktie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0040 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Maroon Bow Tie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0041 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Navy Blue Necktie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0042 (Box 156)
  - Eisenhower "Vote For Ike" Navy Blue Necktie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0043 (Box 156)
  - Stevenson "Gladly for Adlai" Bow Tie, ca. 1952-1956; 2214.WA0044 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower-Nixon Plastic Tie Clasp, ca. 1952-1956; 2214.WA0045 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "Win With Ike For President" Apron, ca. 1952-1956; 2214.WA0046 (Map-case -)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Stockings, ca. 1952-1956; 2214.WA0047 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "Bikes For Ike" Children's T-Shirt, ca. 1952-1956; 2214.WA0048 (Box 82)
  - Republican "Y.C.E.R.B.S.O.Y.A." Handkerchief, ca. 1952-1960; 2214.WA0049 (Box 165)
  - Inaugural Ball Gown, ca. 1953, ca. 1952-1953; 2214.WA0050 (Box TBD)
  - Eisenhower "Support Ike" Suspenders, 1952-1956; 2214.WA0051 (Box 165)
  - Stevenson "I Say Adlai" Brown Necktie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0052 (Box 156)
  - Stevenson "I Say Adlai" Blue Necktie, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0053 (Box 156)
  - Rockefeller "Win With Rocky" Baseball Cap, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0054 (Box 78)
  - "Win With Kennedy" Plastic Portrait Hat, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0055 (Box 151)
  - Kennedy-Johnson Paper Sun Visor, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0056 (Box 138)
  - Nixon "Our Nation Needs Him" Red Garrison Cap, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0057 (Box 141)
  - Nixon "Man Of Steel" Blue Garrison Cap, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0058 (Box 141)
  - Nixon "Man Of Steel" Green Garrison Cap, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0059 (Box 141)
  - "Win With Nixon" Plastic Portrait Hat, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0060 (Box 151)
  - Nixon-Lodge Paper Sun Visor, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0061 (Box 138)
  - "I'm For Nixon" Baseball Cap, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0062 (Box 78)
  - Rockefeller "Rocky in '60" Necktie, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0063 (Box 156)
  - "I'm For Nixon" Bow Tie, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0064 (Box 165)
  - "Kennedy For President" Bow Tie, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0065 (Box 165)
  - "I'm For Nixon" Plastic Traveling Case and Slippers, ca. 1960; 2214.WA0066 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower "Ike" Women's Belt Attachment, ca. 1956; 2214.WA0067 (Box 165)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Title
Call Number
Mr. Roosevelt and the Presidency, ca. 1904
Rare E 757 W62
Theodore Roosevelt's Confession of Faith, 1912
Rare ++ E 757.2 R78 P18 v.3
A Democratic Peace Offered for the Acceptance of Pennsylvania Voters, 1864
Rare E 464.C585 v. 90 no. 21
Address of the Republican General Committee of Young Men of the City and County of New-York, 1828
Rare E 380 D38
The Life and Services of Gen. Geo. B. McClellan, ca. 1864
Rare E 458.4 P76 No. 4
The Life, Speeches, and Public Services of Abram Lincoln, 1860
Rare E457 L72